http://www.jessops.com/c/help/privacypolicy

Privacy Policy
It is our legal obligation to protect our customers' data. The way your data is processed is outlined below.
Home
Help
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
We are Jessops Europe Limited, an English company (Jessops).
Our registered address Network House Third Avenue, Globe Park, Marlow, Buckinghamshire, SL7 1EY.
We are registered with the Information Commissioner’s Office as a data controller with registration number Z3615965.
When you purchase products from our website
When you purchase goods from Jessops website, Jessops will use your personal information to complete your purchase. The details Jessops collect from you will include your name, address, email address, phone number and payment details.When you purchase goods from the Jessops Photo website, If you use Jessops Photo storage and printing services, the data Jessops holds about you and others will depend on the content of the photos you are uploading to the platform. To complete your purchase, we share your personal information with our subcontractors who are involved in the purchase process, such as payment providers, as well as credit reference agencies who we use to assess fraud, credit and/or security risks.For Jessops Photo, we also use subcontractors to operate our online photo printing and storage platform.If you access your images on Google Photo your data may be used and may include:Information about the apps, browsers and devices you use to access their servicesInformation about your activity whilst using the serviceInformation about your locationPlease refer to the Google Privacy Policy https://policies.google.com/privacyWe need to process your personal information in this way to enter into and perform the contract for the item you have purchased from us.
When you collect photos or purchase products in store
As with an online purchase, when you purchase goods from us in store, we will use your personal information to complete your purchase. The details we collect from you will include your name, address, payment and other contact details.
To complete your purchase, we share your personal information with our subcontractors who are involved in the purchase process, such as payment providers, as well as credit reference agencies who we use to assess fraud, credit and/or security risks.
We need to process your personal information in this way to enter into and perform the contract for the item you have purchased from us
When you phone us or use our website chat service
When you phone us or message us using our website chat service, we may also handle your personal information (your name, contact details and the other details you provide to us) in order to provide the customer services you have asked us to. This could be when you ask us to confirm whether a particular product is available or explain how our delivery or returns process works.
We rely on your consent to handle your personal information in this way. If you do not provide us with the personal information we request from you for customer services purposes, we may not be able to fully answer your queries.
When you have expressed an interest in our products
If you have opted in via our website or over the telephone to receive marketing communications from us, we will handle your personal information (such as your name, email address, postal address and telephone number) to provide you with marketing communications in line with any preferences you have told us about.
When we send you marketing emails, we rely on your consent to contact you for marketing purposes. Every email we send to you for marketing purposes will also contain instructions on how to unsubscribe from receiving them.
You are not under any obligation to provide us with your personal data for marketing purposes. We will also occasionally contact you to ensure you are happy to continue receiving electronic marketing communications from us.
You can tell us that you do not want your personal information to be processed in this way at any time by contacting us at cs@jessops.com or, where relevant, by following the unsubscribe link shown in every marketing communication you receive from us.
To make our site and Apps better
We will use your personal information to:
Provide you with a more effective user experience (such as by displaying products we think you will be interested in, based on your purchase history and browsing habits).
Remind you about incomplete purchases, if you are logged into your online account and don’t complete a purchase.
Make our site more secure, to troubleshoot problems and for testing, research and statistical purposes.
If you use the Jessops Photo App, we use a tool provided by Mixpanel to understand how our users interact with the App. The personal information we collect when you use the App includes your location, the device you are using, how you interact with the App and whether you have used the App before.
We also share aggregated, anonymous data with Google to help us optimise our site.
We process your data for these reasons because we have a legitimate interest to provide you with the best experience we can, to improve our site, and make sure it’s kept secure.
You can prevent us from using your personal information in this way by using the 'do not track' functionality in your internet browser. If you enable do not track functionality, our site may be less tailored to your needs and preferences.
If we use Mixpanel’s cookies rather than their server-side functionality, we also need to add a line in to the cookies section of the policy (naming the cookie with a sentence on what it does).
If our business is sold
We will transfer your personal information to a third party:
• If we sell or buy any business or assets, we will provide your personal information to the seller or buyer (but only to the extent we need to, and always in accordance with data protection legislation); or
• If Jessops or the majority of its assets are acquired by somebody else, in which case the personal information held by Jessops will be transferred to the buyer.
We process your personal information for this purpose because we have a legitimate interest to ensure our business can be continued by the buyer. If you object to our use of your personal information in this way, the relevant seller or buyer of our business may not be able to provide services to you.
In some circumstances we may also need to share your personal information if we are under a duty to disclose or share it to comply with a legal obligation.
Information we collect about you
When you visit our site, we will automatically collect the following information:
• Technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, screen resolution, operating system and platform; and
• Information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators, clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time), page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs) and methods used to browse away from the page.
Information we receive from other sources
We are also working closely with third party advertising networks, analytics providers, hosting providers and search information providers from whom we may also receive general aggregated anonymous information about you.
We will combine the information you provide to us with information we collect about you
Why do we use cookies?
Our site uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our site. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our site and also allows us to improve our site. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.
What is a cookie?
A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer. We only use (and store) non-essential cookies on your computer's browser or hard drive if you provide your consent.
Jessops.com This cookie is used to set various preferences for the website, for example a list of recently viewed products. It also sets parameters for some third-party analytics providers e.g. Google.
Doubleclick.net This cookie is part of Google’s advertising network. It is used to provide engaging and relevant advertising to the end user. No personally identifiable information is stored in this cookie. Depending on user settings information contained in this cookie may be added to the user’s account.
Hotjar.com Hotjar enables us to better understand how people are using our site through providing analytics, feedback and using a cookie to track how users click, tap and scroll.
Fresh Relevance This is a service which helps us manage some of the promotions and merchandise we display on the website (banners, selected cameras, drones, lens etc.) and to help you to make sure you don’t miss out on a great offer from us. The cookie enables us to email you a reminder if you have started, but not completed a purchase after you have filled in your email address. We also do this if you are just browsing our website, but you have given us your email address previously. This service is designed to helps us provide you with a great user experience, and we will not use this email to send you other communications unless you specifically ask us to. To manage your cookie preferences in relation to this tool at any time, please see their cookie policy: https://www.freshrelevance.com/cookies-policy
Rakuten Marketing – Use of Rakuten’s platform allows us to work with a wide variety of publishers and websites who advertise for us. Cookies are used to track those who purchase from us or who have clicked on our adverts in the Rakuten network. To understand more on how Rakuten uses your information, and to manage your cookie preferences in relation to this platform at any time, please see their cookie policy - https://rakutenmarketing.com/en-uk/legal-notices/services-privacy-policy
Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, which we do not have any control over. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.
You can block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.
Except for essential cookies, all cookies will expire after 2 years.
Blocking or restricting Cookies
You can stop Cookies being used on your device by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to block the deployment of all or some Cookies. Please visit www.allaboutcookies.org to find out how. Please note, if you use your browser settings to block Cookies you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.
Where is my data stored?
All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers or those of our third party data storage providers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. You must not share your password with anyone.
Many of the third parties we work with who help us run our business are based outside the European Economic Area (EEA). Because of this, their processing of your personal information will often involve it being transferred outside of the EEA.
Whenever we transfer your personal information outside of the EEA, we ensure it is protected by making sure at least one of the following safeguards is in place:
by transferring your personal information to a country that has been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection by the European Commission;
by using specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give your personal information the same legal protection it has as if it never left the EEA; and
where we use organisations based in the United States, we may transfer your personal information to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield, which requires them to provide similar protections to those your personal information has when it is in the EEA.
To keep this privacy policy as short and easy to understand as possible, we have not set out the specific circumstances when each of these protection measures are used. You can contact us at cs@jessops.com for the details as to how we protect specific transfers of your data.
How long do we retain your data for?
Where you have purchased goods from us, we will retain your data for a period of 6 years for legal purposes, to ensure that we are able to assist you should you have any questions, feedback or issues in connection with a product you have purchased from us or if any legal issues arise.
If you tell us that you no longer wish to receive marketing communications from us, we promise to stop sending them to you and will delete any additional data we no longer need to hold about you within 90 days of your unsubscribe request.
Where we have processed your data for any other reason (such as where you have contacted us with a question in connection with potentially purchasing a product) we will retain your data for 2 years.
If you upload photos to your account for the purposes of our photo printing products and services, we will retain those photos for up to 6 months.
Your right to object under data protection laws
You have the right to object to us handling your personal information when:
• we are handling your personal information based on our legitimate interests (as described in the “How do you use my data” section above). If you ask us to stop handling your personal information in this way, we will stop unless we can show you that we have compelling grounds as to why our use of your personal information should continue; or
• for marketing purposes. If you ask us to stop handling your personal information on this basis, we will stop.
What are my rights under data protection laws?
You have various rights under the data protection laws, which you can exercise by contacting us. The easiest way to do this is by email at cs@jessops.com
Right of access
You are entitled to receive confirmation as to whether your personal information is being processed by us, as well as various other details relating to our use of your personal information.
You also have the right to access your personal information which we are handling.
Right to rectification
You have the right to require us to rectify any inaccurate personal information we hold about you.
You also have the right to have incomplete personal information we hold about you completed, by providing a supplementary statement to us.
Right to restriction
You can restrict our processing of your personal information where:
• You think we hold inaccurate personal information about you;
• Our handling of your personal information breaks the law, but you do not want us to delete it;
• We no longer need to process your personal information, but you want us to keep it for legal reasons; or
• Where we are handling your personal information because we have a legitimate interest (as described in the “How We Use Your Data” section above, and are in the process of objecting to this use of your personal information.
Where you exercise your right to restrict us from using your personal information, we will then only process your personal information when you agree, except for storage purposes and to handle legal claims.
Right to data portability
You have the right to receive the personal information we hold about you in a structured, standard machine readable format and to send this to another organisation controlling your personal information.
Right to erasure
You have the right to require us to erase your personal information which we are handling in the following circumstances
• Where we no longer need to use your personal information for the reasons we told you we collected it for;
• Where we needed your consent to use your personal information and you have withdrawn your consent;
• When you object to our use of your personal information and we have no compelling reason to carry on handling your personal information;
• If our handling of your personal information has broken the law; or
• When we must erase your personal information to comply with a law we are subject to.
Right to complain
You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner's Office, the supervisory authority for data protection issues in England and Wales.
Websites we link to
Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks and affiliates.
Our site connects you to different websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites or use our services, please note that you have left our site and these websites have their own privacy policies.
We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies or websites. Please check their policies before you submit any personal information to these websites.
Changes
Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail or post.
Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.
Contact
Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to cs@jessops.com
Sign up for our latest news and offers
Receive the best offers right to your inbox by signing up to our newsletter
Thank You
Email Address
Subscribe
